<boardmember id="bokowski" type="committer">

	<name>Boris Bokowski</name>

	<title>Senior Software Developer</title>

	<image>bokowski.jpg</image>

	<email>Boris_Bokowski@ca.ibm.com</email>

	<eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[
		Platform UI technical lead, member of the Eclipse Architecture Council, 
		e4 committer.
	]]> </eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision>  <![CDATA[
<p>If elected as a committer representative on the Eclipse Board of Directors, I would 
like to help <b>ensure the health and long-term success</b> of Eclipse.</p>

<p>In particular, the following topics would be on my agenda:</p>

<p><b>Make the life of committers easier.</b><br>
We committers are doing much more than just writing code. Many of us enjoy the writing 
code part more than doing all the other necessary activities, for example, triaging b
ugs, managing lists of tasks in Bugzilla, filing contribution questionnaires and 
working through the IP process, ensuring proper internationalization, maintaining 
the IP log. Some of these have become easier recently, thanks to the previous 
committer representatives, and the Eclipse Foundation staff.<br>
I believe that there are many more opportunities for streamlining and 
simplification. At the board level, I would push for improvements, and 
for spending foundation money on this if necessary. Things that come to 
mind are usability improvements for Bugzilla, better performance for CVS/Subversion, 
Bugzilla and the wiki.<br>
In addition to this, I would argue that money would be well spent on work that 
benefits all projects but never gets done because there is not enough benefit 
for each individual project on its own: Compiling and maintaining 
a "new project jumpstart documentation" package, for example. Or coming up 
with a set of exemplary project pages as something the projects could copy and adapt.</p>

<p><b>Increase and improve communication within the community.</b><br>
I believe we could do much more as a community by improving how we communicate. Those 
of us who hang out on IRC know how much they benefit from being able to ask a question 
and quickly get an answer, but also how useful it is to know people working on 
other projects. In addition to trying to get more people on IRC :-), I have other 
ideas how we could improve communication and cross-project interaction.<br>
For example, I like the demo camps because you get to know others in the community. 
How about sponsoring committer and contributor camps once a year, focusing on 
how we get the work done, instead of on the products and projects that are the 
result of that work?<br>
Another way to foster communication would be to make dependency relationships 
transparent. The Foundation already provides data on CVS commits. It should be 
relatively easy to extend this to show, at the granularity of individual plug-ins, 
a list of committers who are currently maintaining each plug-in, and the Eclipse-wide 
dependency relationships between those plug-ins. From a perspective of the Platform, we 
would know who to contact about planned changes to, say, the Common Navigator, and 
in the other direction, it would be easy to find out who maintains, say, the draw2d 
component.<br>
I would also like to see more contacts between Eclipse and other open source 
communities such as Apache, Mozilla, Linux, and so on. A lot of the issues 
that we have around how to attract contributors, how to get companies to 
invest in open source, how to handle issues of APIs and deprecation, and 
so on, must be issues in these other communities as well, and we should be 
able to learn from each other.</p> 

<p><b>Prepare ourselves for change.</b><br>
It is mind-boggling to see the rate of change in several areas that affect 
Eclipse directly. I don't know what the best answers are, but I know that we 
have a number of open questions and am interested in discussing them at the 
board level, for example:<br>
<ul><li>The world-wide economic problems are affecting all Eclipse members, 
including the committer members through their employers and customers. This is both 
a threat, in that it is going to be harder for companies to fund 
development in the Eclipse context, and an opportunity, in that adoption of 
and collaboration through open source solutions could increase.</li>

<li>The technology context is becoming more and more fragmented. For example, 
Java is  no longer the "cool language" of choice for developers, and web UIs 
start to become more important than desktop UIs. At Eclipse, we mainly develop 
using Java, and provide mostly desktop UIs. All stakeholders will have to 
help change this (in the long term) to avoid ending up in a technological dead end.</li>

<li>The number of Eclipse member companies, Eclipse projects, and Eclipse 
committers has increased dramatically. I suspect that our current structure 
(e.g. development process, PMCs, councils) will have to change to enable 
more scaling but I don't see this discussed.</li>
</ul></p>

	]]> </vision>

	<bio> <![CDATA[ <p>
Boris is the technical lead of the Eclipse Platform UI component and works 
for IBM in Ottawa, Canada. He is a member of the Eclipse Architecture Council, 
and an active committer on the e4 project. He is proud to have helped increase 
diversity at the Eclipse Platform (a little) by attracting several non-IBM 
contributors and helping them become committers. Before joining IBM in 2005, 
he wrote a commercial RCP app using EMF and GEF, co-founded and co-managed 
a Web 2.0 company in Germany, worked on the original Eclipse 1.0 at OTI in 
Ottawa, and earned a PhD in computer science at Freie Universit&auml;t Berlin, 
Germany. He is married and a geek dad of three kids. You can find him on 
IRC as "borisb6i".	</p>	
	]]> </bio>

	<affiliation> <![CDATA[ 
		IBM Software, Ottawa, Canada
	]]>
	</affiliation>

		
</boardmember>