<boardmember id="brede" type="addin">

	<name>Hans-Joachim Brede</name>

	<title></title>

	<image>brede.jpg</image>

	<email>hans-joachim.brede@bredex.de</email>

	<eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[\
Bredex GmbH joined the Eclipse Foundation as Solution Members in 2007. As well as using Eclipse as an IDE, we also offer RCP training. Members of Bredex have worked as contributors and committers on Eclipse projects. 
		
	]]> </eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision>  <![CDATA[
My vision for Eclipse in 2009 is to encourage more contact between European and American members. The growth of the Eclipse community on both sides of the Atlantic is a great opportunity for member companies and individuals to network and share ideas. As a representative based in Europe I can collect and present ideas from a European perspective as well as communicating other ideas back to the members in Europe. The issues and questions of European members play an important role in moving Eclipse on as a platform and as a community. I would like to be the point-of-contact for both sides to bring us closer together. 
		

	]]> </vision>

	<bio> <![CDATA[
Hans-Joachim (Achim) Brede is the founder of BREDEX GmbH and is one of its managing directors. He has implemented and managed multiple, highly complex customer projects and is responsible for the concepts in the development of the automated test tool GUIdancer. Achim holds a Master in Computer Science and has worked with the University of Braunschweig and Digital Equipment as a technical consultant.
		
	]]> </bio>\

	<affiliation> <![CDATA[ 
		
Since 1987, BREDEX GmbH has been providing high quality information technology
services in the areas of consultancy, analysis and design, software development and
training. Based in Braunschweig, the company has a history of long term customer
satisfaction and a focus on forward thinking, developing individual solutions that bring
future standards to current project needs. BREDEX sells GUIdancer, which is a powerful
and cost effective automatic test tool for Java and HTML applications.
	
	]]>
	</affiliation>

</boardmember>