
<boardmember id="gaff" type="committer">

	<name>Doug Gaff</name>

	<title>Senior Managerm Wind River and DSDP PMC Lead</title>

	<image>gaff.jpg</image>

	<email>doug.gaff@windriver.com</email>


	<eclipse_affiliation>
		<![CDATA[
		<ul>
		<li>Eclipse Board of Directors 2008-2009</li>
		<li>DSDP PMC Lead</li>
		<li>EclipseCon 2008 Program Committee Chair</li>
		<li>Planning and Architecture Councils</li>
		<li>Project Mentor</li>
		</ul>
		]]>
	</eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision> 
		<![CDATA[
    <P>I've been serving on the Board as your elected Committer Representative for almost a year now. Here are some of 
    my personal accomplishments in this role so far:</p>
    <ul>
    <li> I've been blogging the minutes of the face-to-face board meetings 
         (<a href="http://eclipse-committer-reps.blogspot.com/2008/06/june-board-meeting.html">June</a>, 
         <a href="http://eclipse-committer-reps.blogspot.com/2008/09/september-board-meeting.html">September</a>, 
         <a href="http://eclipse-committer-reps.blogspot.com/2008/12/december-2008-board-meeting.html">December</a>) 
         to enable more immediate transparency of Board activities.</li>
    <li> I proposed and received approval for dual licensing (EPL/EDL) for the embedded runtime components in the 
         RTSC and TM projects. This kicked off a bigger discussion (led by Jeff McAffer) about dual licensing runtimes 
         and the need to encourage runtime reference implementations in Eclipse. </li>
    <li> I proposed Japanese localization of the Bugzilla interface, which was approved and will be completed when 
         Bugzilla 3.2 is deployed. </li>
    <li> In the interest of representing the user community, Mik and I facilitated a sometimes contentious discussion 
         with the Board about the customer-facing messaging of the Eclipse train release. </li>
    <li> I presented several requests from the Architecture Council (see December minutes), with somewhat mixed results. </li>
    <li> I serve on the Compensation Committee. The Comp Committee works with the Executive Director to establish 
         quarterly objectives for the Director and Foundation. The Comp Committee also conducts the annual performance 
         review for the Director. </li>
    </ul>
    <p>So why do I want you to elect me for another term?</p>
    <ul>
    <li> I believe I'm doing a good job representing committer issues, even when those issues don't align with the 
         Board's interests. Much of my individual accomplishments above are focused on this effort. </li>
    <li> I want to continue working with the rest of the Board on the strategy for the Foundation and ecosystem. 
         I believe my execution skills and sense of vision will continue to be valuable as we guide the Foundation 
         through these financially challenging times. </li>
    <li> I'd like to continue my work on the Compensation Committee, as it is directly tied to the execution of the 
         Eclipse strategy. </li>
    <li> Working on the Board has been an excellent learning experience so far, and I'd like to continue learning. </li>
    </ul>
		]]>	
	</vision>

	<bio> 
		<![CDATA[
		<p>Doug Gaff serves on the Eclipse Board of Directors and is the PMC Lead for the Device Software Development Platform 
		(DSDP) - an Eclipse project focused on building an extensible, standards-based platform to address a broad range of needs 
		in the embedded and mobile software development space. In his commercial life, Doug is a 
		Senior Engineering Manager on Wind River's commercial Eclipse-based product, Wind River Workbench. He is responsible for 
		Eclipse open source contributions and adoption of Eclipse technology commercially. Doug has 14 years of software 
		development and management experience and holds a Bachelors and Masters in Electrical Engineering.</p>	 
		]]>
	</bio>

	<affiliation> 
		<![CDATA[
		Wind River Systems
		]]>
	</affiliation>

		
</boardmember>
