<boardmember id="lenz" type="addin">

    <name>Dr. Mario Lenz</name>
    <title>Chief Technology Officer, empolis</title>

    <image>lenz.jpg</image>

    <email>mario.lenz@empolis.com</email>

    <eclipse_affiliation><![CDATA[
    For empolis, Eclipse is firstly a mature and powerful tool provider in that a lot of components and tools
    of eclipse are in intensive use in product development at empolis, e.g. IDE as well as RCP. This is where
    empolis does not really contribute but rather *consume* only.
    Secondly, even more important, Eclipse is an intrinsic element of empolis' technology portfolio when 
    it comes to developing a new platform and solutions based on and in cooperation with the open source 
    community. empolis in particular appreciates the unique technological expertise provided by the members
    combined with the technical flexibility and economical promises of an open source platform
    that can open the space for commercial applications beyond what is possible in the traditional closed world
    in particular for a company the size of empolis.]]>
    </eclipse_affiliation>

    <vision> <![CDATA[
    My vision as a candidate for the Eclipse Board is: 
-    Support the growth of the Eclipse Ecosystem as a pervasive industrial strength 
        software platform for building runtime solutions with a specific focus on
        Semantic Web technology and unstructured data management. This is the main
        area of empolis and we feel this is generally still a white spot that should
        be occupied by open source even before commercial vendors could claim that space.
-    Help to establish Eclipse in research and education to make sure graduates can 
        seamlessly be integrated into industrial SW production. This also includes
        provisioning of reday-to-use components and framworks to R&D such that research
        institutes can truly focus on their expertise rather than having to develop
        infrastructure technology.
-    Strengthen the influence of European Solution Members in the community
-    Help to drive more technology-focussed projects inside eclipse to delivering
        real value in the sense of customer-oriented solutions
    ]]> </vision>

    <bio> <![CDATA[
    Dr. Mario Lenz completed his Doctorate in Computer Sciences at the Humboldt University in Berlin, 
    majoring in Knowledge Management and minoring in Psychology. During his studies, numerous 
    industrial cooperation projects took place. In 1999 Mario became Director of Development 
    at tec:inno. After the integration of tec:inno into empolis and several management positions 
    in product development, Dr. Lenz was appointed CTO and became a member of the 
    empolis management board in 2006. 
    ]]> </bio>


    <affiliation> 
        empolis GmbH
    </affiliation>

</boardmember>
