<boardmember id="ragan" type="addin">

	<name>Tracy Ragan</name>

	<title>COO, OpenMake Software  </title>

	<image>ragan.jpg</image>

	<email>tracy.ragan@openmakesoftware.com</email>

	<eclipse_affiliation>Sustaining Member <![CDATA[
		
	]]> </eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision>As a member of Eclipse for the last  7 years, I have watched the organization change and grow.  We are entering another one of those times where difficult decisions need to be made with regards to the methods that will be used to keep the Eclipse platform and technology on the leading edge.  My vision for the Eclipse Foundation is two fold.  First, I see the technology it supports moving forward allowing it to remain a primary choice as a development framework.  Secondly, the Eclipse Foundation should push forward with working groups from vertical industries sharing a common technology.  Creating common ground in technology is what the Eclipse Foundation does well.  We should continue down that road, but move up to a super highway where more collaboration within "like" industries is and shared and fostered.  <![CDATA[
		

	]]> </vision>

	<bio>Ms. Ragan has had extensive experience in the development and implementation of business applications. She began her consulting career in 1989 consulting to fortune 500 organizations in the areas of testing, configuration management and build management. It was during her consulting experiences that Ms. Ragan recognized the lack of build management procedures for the distributed platform that had long been considered standard on the mainframe. In the four years leading to the creation of OpenMake Software she worked with development teams in implementing a team-centric standardized build management process. Ms. Ragan currently serves on the Eclipse Foundation Board of Directors as an Sustaining Member Representative.   Ms. Ragan received her Bachelor of Science Degree in Business Administration from California Polytechnic University, Pomona, CA. <![CDATA[
		
	]]> </bio>

	<affiliation> <![CDATA[ 
		
	
	]]>
	</affiliation>

		
</boardmember>