<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<staffmembers version="1.0">
	<staffmember id="wayne">
		<name>Wayne Beaton</name>
		<title>Eclipse Evangelist</title>
		<image>http://www.rokc.ca/wayne/images/blog_waynepolor.jpg</image>
		<description>
			Wayne Beaton is employed by The Eclipse Foundation where he
			works as an evangelist, spreading the word and helping folks
			adopt Eclipse technologies. Wayne has extensive experience
			in object-oriented software development and is a strong
			proponent of refactoring, unit testing, and agile
			development methodologies.
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="janet">
		<name>Janet Campbell</name>
		<title>Manager, Intellectual Property</title>
		<image />
		<description>
		Outside of work, Janet enjoys traveling (to South East Asia in particular), 
		walking her dogs, taking her bike for a spin and spending time with family 
		and friends.  
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="ward">
		<name>Ward Cunningham</name>
		<title>Director, Committer Community Development</title>
		<image />
		<description />
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="bjorn">
		<name>Bjorn Freeman-Benson</name>
		<title>
			Director, Open Source Process
		</title>
		<image />
		<description> <![CDATA[ While striving to be a Renaissance Man, Bjorn keeps falling back into 
			the clutches of conformity with engineering stereotypes such as <A 
			href="http://www.squeak.org/">dynamic languages</A>, <A 
			href="http://www.agilealliance.org/">software engineering</A>, <A 
			href="http://www.juggling.org/">juggling</A> and <A 
			href="http://www.eaa.org/">general aviation</A>. His escape attempts have been 
			through <A href="http://www.orienteering.org/">orienteering</A>, <A 
			href="http://www.bta4bikes.org/">bicycling</A>, <A 
			href="http://www.friendsoftrees.org/">planting trees</A> and <A 
			href="http://www.superboy.org/images/superboy.jpg">painting his airplane</A>. He 
			is passionate about doing things instead of just talking about them, and he 
			thoroughly enjoys the <A href="http://www.eclipsecon.org/">annual party</A> he 
			helps organize for the Eclipse community.]]></description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="skip">
		<name>Skip McGaughey</name>
		<title>Director, Ecosystem</title>
		<image> ../../images/skip.jpg </image>
		<description> <![CDATA[ 
		I have a favorite quote form Robert Kennedy which says... &quot;Some look at the world and ask Why;  
		others strive to create a better world by asking Why Not.&quot;&nbsp;<br/><br/><br/>
		]]></description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="mike">
		<name>Mike Milinkovich</name>
		<title>Executive Director</title>
		<image>../../images/mikemsmall.jpg</image>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[<p>Outside of work, Mike's passions are his family, the family cottage and hockey (as a
			coach, player and fan)
			in pretty much that order. When he's not working, or traveling for work, you will probably
			find him involved in one of those three things. </p>
			<p>You can read Mike's blog at
			<a href="http://milinkovich.blogspot.com/" target="blank">
			http://milinkovich.blogspot.com/</a>.</p>]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="ralph">
		<name>Ralph Mueller</name>
		<title>Director, Ecosystem - Europe</title>
		<image />
		<description />
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="denis">
		<name>Denis Roy</name>
		<title>Manager, IT Infrastructure</title>
		<image>../../images/denis.jpg </image>
		<description>At work, he stares at servers and blinking lights. At play, he enjoys outdoor 
		sports that involve vehicles and gasoline engines. To Denis, life is at its best when he's on 
		his snowmobile at the top of a mountain covered in fresh snow on a calm winter afternoon. 
		Other interests include home renovation, auto mechanics, video games and his soon-to-be 
		daughter.
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="ian">
		<name>Ian Skerrett</name>
		<title>Director, Marketing</title>
		<image />
		<description>
		<![CDATA[ Ian takes care of the marketing activities at the Eclipse Foundation.  
		Although our community is the Eclipse marketing machine,  Ian supports the projects and member 
		companies to increase the awareness of all the cool stuff happening at Eclipse.  
		You can read his blog at <a href="http://ianskerrett.blogspot.com/" target="blank">
		http://ianskerrett.blogspot.com/</a>.]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="matt">
		<name>Matt Ward</name>
		<title>Systems Administrator</title>
		<image />
		<description />
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="sharon">
		<name>Sharon Wolfe</name>
		<title>Office Manager</title>
		<image />
		<description>Sharon has been with the Eclipse Foundation since July 2004.  In addition 
		to her Office Manager responsibilities, Sharon assists with marketing activities and also 
		organizes or assists with the planning of various meetings and conferences.  Sharon thanks 
		Mike every day for opening a proper office because she was going stir crazy working out 
		of the home office in her basement!
		</description>
	</staffmember>


</staffmembers>