<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<staffmembers version="1.0">
	<staffmember id="wayne">
		<name>Wayne Beaton</name>
		<title>Director of Open Source Projects</title>
		<image>../../images/wayne.jpg</image>
		<description><![CDATA[
			<p>Wayne is the Director of Open Source Projects at the Eclipse Foundation. 
			He spends his days working with the many Eclipse projects, learning about 
			Eclipse technology, and making sure that everybody knows just how cool it 
			all really is. When not working, he can usually be found watching his kids
			play hockey at one of the many local arenas.</p>
			<p>Wayne authors the 
			<a href="http://waynebeaton.wordpress.com/" target="blank">Eclipse Hints, Tips, and Random Musings</a> blog.</p>
		]]></description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="janet">
		<name>Janet Campbell</name>
		<title><![CDATA[Director, Intellectual Property<br/>Secretary and Legal Counsel]]></title>
		<image> ../../images/janet.jpg </image>
		<description> <![CDATA[
			<p>Outside of work, Janet enjoys traveling (to South East Asia in particular),
			walking her dogs, taking her bike for a spin and spending time with family
			and friends.</p>
		]]> </description>
	</staffmember>


	<staffmember id="sharonc">
		<name>Sharon Corbett-Gütz</name>
		<image>../../images/sharonc.png</image>
		<title>Intellectual Property Management</title>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[<p>Hailing from the most easterly province in Canada, Sharon is the resident "Newfie" of the Foundation!  Sharon’s main focus is the community’s IP, but she is also passionate about the game of footy.  She continues her on again/off again relationship with running; is devoted to shopping, and strives to improve her appreciation for fine red wine.</p>
		]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="nathan">
		<name>Nathan Gervais</name>
		<image>../../images/nathan.png</image>
		<title>Web Developer</title>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>Keep an eye out for this kid!  Nathan joined 
			Eclipse in 2006 and is usually seen lurking around eclipse.org 
			websites working his magic. Hobbies include playing tennis, 
			spending time with my kids and portaging through Algonquin Park.</p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>
	
		<staffmember id="chrisguindon">
		<name>Christopher Guindon</name>
		<image>../../images/chrisguindon.jpg</image>
		<title>Web Developer</title>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p> When he’s not at a computer, which is rare, Chris spends his time relaxing with his girlfriend and his dog Winston, playing the drums, watching a Habs game or at the top of a hill snowboarding. </p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="tha">
		<name>Thanh Ha</name>
		<title>Release Engineer</title>
		<image> ../../images/tha.jpg </image>
		<description><![CDATA[
			<p>Thanh is an open source enthusiest who loves to tinker with new technology
			 as a user and developer. When not at a computer he enjoys spending time 
			 outside rollerblading.</p>
		]]></description>
	</staffmember>
	
	<staffmember id="anne">
		<name>Anne Jacko</name>
		<image>../../images/anne.png</image>
		<title>Conference Queen</title>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>When not in front of a monitor, Anne prefers activities 
			that involve wearing a helmet--horseback riding, skiing,
			and cycling. One of her favorite books is <i>The Chicago Manual 
			of Style</i>, so if you need help with the nitpicking
			details of writing in English, she's happy to help.</p>]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="pablo">
		<name>Pablo Jacubovich</name>
		<image>../../images/Pablo.jpg</image>
		<title>Intellectual Property Analyst</title>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>Pablo is part of the Intellectual Property team.  When he is not at work he enjoys football
			 (playing and watching), running,  reading, and movies.  He might or might not enjoy these things in 
			 preparation for a zombie apocalypse.</p>]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>


	<staffmember id="roxanne">
		<name>Roxanne Joncas</name>
		<image>../../images/roxanne.jpg</image>
		<title>Marketing and Events Specialist</title>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>Roxanne is the Marketing and Event Specialist at Eclipse. 
			She spends most of her time organizing events and advertising said events. 
			She’s addicted to Pinterest and is a TV/Movie Junkie, but found time to fall in love with yoga, 
			swimming, fashion, baking, and music.</p>]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="perri">
		<name>Perri Lavergne</name>
		<title>Ecosystem Development Support</title>
		<image>../../images/perri.png</image>
		<description> <![CDATA[
			<p>Perri joined the Eclipse Foundation in May 2010. Her focus is on 
			membership retention and development. Outside of work Perri enjoys 
			spending time with family and friends, medical research, volunteer 
			work for organizations dealing with children with special needs, 
			running, cooking and baking. Perri hopes to one day accomplish her 
			long time dream of a unique before and after school program for 
			teens with special needs.</p>
		]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="mike">
		<name>Mike Milinkovich</name>
		<title>Executive Director</title>
		<image>../../images/mikemsmall.jpg</image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>Outside of work, Mike's passions are his family, the family cottage and hockey (as a
			coach, player and fan)
			in pretty much that order. When he's not working, or traveling for work, you will probably
			find him involved in one of those three things. </p>
			<p>You can read Mike's blog at
 <a href="http://mmilinkov.wordpress.com/" target="blank">mmilinkov.wordpress.com/</a>.</p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="ralph">
		<name>Ralph Mueller</name>
		<title>Director, Ecosystem - Europe</title>
		<image>../../images/ralph.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>
			Ralph's role at the Eclipse Foundation is focused on growing 
			the Eclipse Ecosystem
			across Europe. </p>
			<p>Ralph's passion outside of work is golf, both as a player 
			and as a coach for children just starting the game. He's also 
			helped both Mike and Donald to improve their games.</p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="andrew">
		<name>Andrew Ross</name>
		<title>Director, Ecosystem</title>
		<image>../../images/andrew.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>
			Andrew is responsible for the <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/LTS">long term support</a>, 
			<a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/Location">Location</a>, and <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/CBI">Common Build Infrastructure</a>
			programs. He's also good guy to ask about VoIP technology and <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/Asterisk">Asterisk</a>. 
			</p>
			<p>Andrew can't help but be drawn to useful technology.
			Being a Husband and Dad fills his life with much joy. 
			When there's time left over, Andrew enjoys viewing the night
			sky with a telescope.
			</p>
			<p>
			<a href="https://42aross.wordpress.com/" target="blank">
Read Andrew's Blog</a>
			</p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="denis">
		<name>Denis Roy</name>
		<title>Director, IT Services</title>
		<image>../../images/denis_t.png</image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>In the office, Denis spends his time in front of a Linux command prompt.  Leisure activities include going to the cottage with his kids, drag racing and snowmobiling.</p><p>You can read his <a href="http://eclipsewebmaster.blogspot.com/" target="blank">blog</a>,  and view the <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/index.php/WebMaster" target="_blank">Eclipse Webmaster</a> page.</p>]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="ian">
		<name>Ian Skerrett</name>
		<title>Director, Marketing</title>
		<image>../../images/ian.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>Ian takes care of the marketing activities at the Eclipse Foundation.
			Although our community is the Eclipse marketing machine,  Ian supports the projects and member
			companies to increase the awareness of all the cool stuff happening at Eclipse.
			You can read his blog at <a href="http://ianskerrett.wordpress.com/" target="blank">http://ianskerrett.wordpress.com/</a>.</p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>


	<staffmember id="matt">
		<name>Matt Ward</name>
		<title>Systems Administrator</title>
		<image> ../../images/mattfire.jpg </image>
		<description><![CDATA[
			<p>Matt spends his time triaging the Webmaster inbox and putting out 
			fires.  If you can't take the heat, stay out of the data center.</p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="sharon">
		<name>Sharon Wolfe</name>
		<title>Office Manager</title>
		<image> ../../images/sharon.jpg </image>
		<description><![CDATA[
			<p>Sharon has been with the Eclipse Foundation since July 2004.  As Office Manager,
			 Sharon is the keeper of all agreements, manages the invoicing and membership renewal processes,
			  accounts receivables and provides administrative support for the Executive Director and the Director, 
			  Operations and the Board of Directors.  Family, friends, 3 dogs and her horse take up her 
			  time away from the office. </p>
		]]></description>
	</staffmember>
</staffmembers>
