<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<staffmembers version="1.0">
	<staffmember id="wayne">
		<name>Wayne Beaton</name>
		<title>Eclipse Evangelist</title>
		<image>../../images/polarbear.gif</image>
		<description>
			Wayne is the Director of Open Source Projects at the Eclipse Foundation. 
			He spends his days working with the many Eclipse projects, learning about 
			Eclipse technology, and making sure that everybody knows just how cool it 
			all really is. Wayne is also the editor-in-chief of Eclipse Corner, PMC 
			member of the Mylyn, Technology, and TPTP Projects, Project Lead for the 
			Dash, Examples, and Woolsey Projects, and an advisor for osbootcamp. In 
			1982, he received the prestigious Chief Scouts Award from then-Governor 
			General Edward Schreyer. In 1984 his team was selected to represent 
			beautiful British Columbia in the Kinsmen Voyageur Relay. In his spare 
			time, he writes down meaningless accomplishments from his youth in a 
			lame attempt to impress the reader.
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="janet">
		<name>Janet Campbell</name>
		<title><![CDATA[Director, Intellectual Property]]></title>
		<image> ../../images/janet.jpg </image>
		<description> <![CDATA[
			<p>Outside of work, Janet enjoys traveling (to South East Asia in particular),
			walking her dogs, taking her bike for a spin and spending time with family
			and friends.</p>
		]]> </description>
	</staffmember>


	<staffmember id="sharonc">
		<name>Sharon Corbett-Gütz</name>
		<image>../../images/sharonc.jpg</image>
		<title>Intellectual Property Management</title>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[<p>When remote from Eclipse, Sharon C. is a fulltime soccer mom and dedicated footie fan.  Sharon can usually be found
		heading out with her son to a practice, game or tournament.</p>
		<br/>
		]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="nathan">
		<name>Nathan Gervais</name>
		<image>../../images/nathan.png</image>
		<title>Web Developer</title>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>Keep an eye out for this kid!  Nathan joined Eclipse in 2006 and is usually seen lurking around eclipse.org websites working his magic.
			Hobbies include playing tennis, walking his dog, and working on whatever his latest project is!</p>
			<br/>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="anne">
		<name>Anne Jacko</name>
		<image>../../images/anne.png</image>
		<title>Conference Queen</title>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[When not in front of a monitor, Anne prefers activities that involve wearing a helmet--horseback riding, skiing,
			and cycling. One of her favorite books is <i>The Chicago Manual of Style</i>, so if you need help with the nitpicking
			details of writing in English, she's happy to help.]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="allison">
		<name>Allison Kelly</name>
		<title><![CDATA[Ecosystem Development Support]]></title>
		<image> ../../images/allison.jpg </image>
		<description> <![CDATA[
			<p>Allison joined the Eclipse Foundation in March 2009.  Her focus is on membership
			retention and supporting business development. Outside of work she enjoys cooking,
			traveling, spending time with family and friends and dreams of living in a warmer
			climate someday!</p>
		]]> </description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="perri">
		<name>Perri Lavergne</name>
		<title>Ecosystem Development Support</title>
		<image>../../images/perri.png</image>
		<description> <![CDATA[
			<p>Perri joined the Eclipse Foundation in May 2010. Her focus is on membership retention and development. Outside of work Perri enjoys spending time with family and friends, medical research, volunteer work for organizations dealing with children with special needs, running, cooking and baking. Perri hopes to one day accomplish her long time dream of a unique before and after school program for teens with special needs.</p>
		]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="mike">
		<name>Mike Milinkovich</name>
		<title>Executive Director</title>
		<image>../../images/mikemsmall.jpg</image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>Outside of work, Mike's passions are his family, the family cottage and hockey (as a
			coach, player and fan)
			in pretty much that order. When he's not working, or traveling for work, you will probably
			find him involved in one of those three things. </p>
			<p>You can read Mike's blog at
 <a href="http://dev.eclipse.org/blogs/mike/" target="blank">
http://dev.eclipse.org/blogs/mike/</a>.</p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="ralph">
		<name>Ralph Mueller</name>
		<title>Director, Ecosystem - Europe</title>
		<image>../../images/ralph.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>
			Ralph's role at the Eclipse Foundation is focused on growing the Eclipse Ecosystem
			across Europe. </p>
			<p>Ralph's passion outside of work is golf, both as a player and as a coach for children
			just starting the game. He's also helped both Mike and Donald to improve their games.
			</p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="denis">
		<name>Denis Roy</name>
		<title>Director, IT Services</title>
		<image>../../images/denis.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>In the office, Denis spends his time in front of a Linux command prompt.  Leisure activities include going to the cottage with my daughter, drag racing and snowmobiling.<br /><br />You can read his <a href="http://eclipsewebmaster.blogspot.com/" target="blank">blog</a>, and view the <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/index.php/WebMaster" target="_blank">Eclipse Webmaster</a> page.</p><br/><br/>]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="ian">
		<name>Ian Skerrett</name>
		<title>Director, Marketing</title>
		<image>../../images/ian.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[ Ian takes care of the marketing activities at the Eclipse Foundation.
			Although our community is the Eclipse marketing machine,  Ian supports the projects and member
			companies to increase the awareness of all the cool stuff happening at Eclipse.
			You can read his blog at <a href="http://ianskerrett.wordpress.com/" target="blank">http://ianskerrett.wordpress.com/</a>.
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="donald">
		<name>Donald Smith</name>
		<title>Director, Ecosystem Development</title>
		<image> ../../images/donald.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[
			After a very busy 2005 completing an MBA, designing a new house and getting
			married, Donald joined Eclipse to begin 2006 with his now seemingly infinite
			free time.  Donald has over a decade of experience with enterprise software
			including product management, marketing, engineering and consulting.  He has
			spoken on various topics at most major Java conferences including Java One,
			TSSS, JAOO, CSS, Sun Tech Days and others.  Donald's role at Eclipse is to
			help foster the development of the ecosystem.
			<br/> &nbsp; <br/>
			You can read Donald's blog at <a href="http://eclipse-ecosystem.blogspot.com/" target="blank">
			http://eclipse-ecosystem.blogspot.com/</a>.
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="matt">
		<name>Matt Ward</name>
		<title>Systems Administrator</title>
		<image> ../../images/mattfire.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[ Matt spends his time triaging the Webmaster inbox and putting out fires.  If you can't take the heat,
			 stay out of the data center. 
			&nbsp; <br/> &nbsp; <br/>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>


	<staffmember id="sharon">
		<name>Sharon Wolfe</name>
		<title>Office Manager</title>
		<image> ../../images/sharon.jpg </image>
		<description>
			Sharon has been with the Eclipse Foundation since July 2004.  In addition
			to her Office Manager responsibilities, Sharon assists with marketing activities and also
			organizes or assists with the planning of various meetings and conferences.  Sharon thanks
			Mike every day for opening a proper office because she was going stir crazy working out
			of the home office in her basement!
		</description>
	</staffmember>

</staffmembers>