<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<staffmembers version="1.0">
	<staffmember id="wayne">
		<name>Wayne Beaton</name>
		<title>Eclipse Evangelist</title>
		<image>../../images/polarbear.gif</image>
		<description>
			Wayne Beaton is employed by The Eclipse Foundation where he
			works as an evangelist, spreading the word and helping folks
			adopt Eclipse technologies. Wayne has extensive experience
			in object-oriented software development and is a strong
			proponent of refactoring, unit testing, and agile
			development methodologies.
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="janet">
		<name>Janet Campbell</name>
		<title><![CDATA[ Legal Counsel & Manager, Intellectual Property]]></title>
		<image> ../../images/janet.jpg </image>
		<description> <![CDATA[ 
			<p>Outside of work, Janet enjoys traveling (to South East Asia in particular), 
			walking her dogs, taking her bike for a spin and spending time with family 
			and friends.</p>
		]]> </description>
	</staffmember>
	
	<staffmember id="barb">
		<name>Barb Cochrane</name>
		<image>../../images/barb.jpg</image>
		<title>Intellectual Property Management</title>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[
				Barb joined Eclipse in August 2007.  Outside Eclipse, Barb likes to travel, 
				cook and spend time with family and friends.  During the winter months, she 
				occasionally finds new ways to injure herself while skating on the canal or
				 flailing down one of the local ski hills.</p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>
	
	<staffmember id="sharonc">
		<name>Sharon Corbett</name>
		<image>../../images/sharonc.jpg</image>
		<title>Intellectual Property Analyst</title>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[<p>When remote from Eclipse, Sharon C. is a fulltime soccer mom and dedicated footie fan.  Sharon can usually be found
		heading out with her son to a practice, game or tournament.</p> 
		<br/>
		]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>	

	
	<staffmember id="bjorn">
		<name>Bjorn Freeman-Benson</name>
		<title>
			Director, Committer Community
		</title>
		<image> ../../images/bjorn.jpg </image>
		<description> <![CDATA[ While striving to be a Renaissance Man, Bjorn keeps falling back into 
			the clutches of conformity with engineering stereotypes such as <A 
			href="http://www.squeak.org/">dynamic languages</A>, <A 
			href="http://www.agilealliance.org/">software engineering</A>, <A 
			href="http://www.juggling.org/">juggling</A> and <A 
			href="http://www.eaa.org/">general aviation</A>. His escape attempts have been 
			through <A href="http://www.orienteering.org/">orienteering</A>, <A 
			href="http://www.bta4bikes.org/">bicycling</A>, <A 
			href="http://www.friendsoftrees.org/">planting trees</A> and <A 
			href="http://www.superboy.org/images/superboy.jpg">painting his airplane</A>. He 
			is passionate about doing things instead of just talking about them, and he 
			thoroughly enjoys the <A href="http://www.eclipsecon.org/">annual party</A> he 
			helps organize for the Eclipse community.
			<p>You can read Bjorn's blog at
			<a href="http://eclipse-projects.blogspot.com/" target="blank">
			http://eclipse-projects.blogspot.com/</a>.</p>
			]]></description>
	</staffmember>
	
	<staffmember id="lynn">
		<name>Lynn Gayowski</name>
		<image>../../images/lynn.jpg</image>
		<title>Marketing Events Manager</title>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>Lynn moved from Winnipeg to join Eclipse in 2006.  When Lynn isn&rsquo;t organizing marketing events, she enjoys
			geocaching, rollerblading and raising her rabbit.</p> 
			<br>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>
	
	<staffmember id="nathan">
		<name>Nathan Gervais</name>
		<image>../../images/nathan.png</image>
		<title>Web Developer</title>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>Keep an eye out for this kid!  Besides lurking around eclipse.org he can be seen playing tennis, walking his dog, and
			driving his new car!</p>
			<br/>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="anne">
		<name>Anne Jacko</name>
		<image>../../images/anne.jpg</image>
		<title>Development Process Operations Support</title>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[When not in front of a monitor, Anne prefers activities that involve wearing a helmet--horseback riding, skiing,
			and (fair-weather) cycling. One of her favorite books is The Chicago Manual of Style, so if you need help with the nitpicking
			details of writing in English, she's happy to help.]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="karl">
		<name>Karl Matthias</name>
		<title>Systems Administrator</title>
		<image></image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[Karl is the Portland arm of the IT team and isn't the "new guy" at the Foundation any more (thanks Chris!).
			When he's not supporting the infrastructure, working on the portal, or knocking items off of Bjorn's wish list, he's in the
			garage restoring his 1969 Alfa Romeo GTV.
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="mike">
		<name>Mike Milinkovich</name>
		<title>Executive Director</title>
		<image>../../images/mikemsmall.jpg</image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>Outside of work, Mike's passions are his family, the family cottage and hockey (as a
			coach, player and fan)
			in pretty much that order. When he's not working, or traveling for work, you will probably
			find him involved in one of those three things. </p>
			<p>You can read Mike's blog at
			<a href="http://milinkovich.blogspot.com/" target="blank">
			http://milinkovich.blogspot.com/</a>.</p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="ralph">
		<name>Ralph Mueller</name>
		<title>Director, Ecosystem - Europe</title>
		<image>../../images/ralph.jpg </image>
		<description> 
			<![CDATA[<p>
			Ralph's role at the Eclipse Foundation is focused on growing the Eclipse Ecosystem
			across Europe. </p>
			<p>Ralph's passion outside of work is golf, both as a player and as a coach for children 
			just starting the game. He's also helped both Mike and Donald to improve their games.
			</p>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

    <staffmember id="gabe">
    	<name>Gabe O'Brien</name>
    	<title>Darn Good Programmer</title>
		<image>../../images/gabe.jpg </image>
    	<description>
	    	<![CDATA[<p>
	    	Being a darn good developer takes time, patience, and a good sense of humor.  
	    	Beside hacking away at code, Gabe enjoys silk screening on anything that will 
	    	sit still, working in the garden, and writing poetry (which is a lot like 
	    	writing code only everyone can read it).</p>
	    	]]>
    	</description>
    </staffmember>
    
	<staffmember id="denis">
		<name>Denis Roy</name>
		<title>Manager, IT Infrastructure</title>
		<image>../../images/denis.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>Denis spends too much time in front of a command prompt. 
			You can read his <a href="http://eclipsewebmaster.blogspot.com/" target="blank">blog</a>, 
			and view the <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/index.php/WebMaster" target="_blank">Eclipse Webmaster</a> page.</p>
			<br/><br/>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="ian">
		<name>Ian Skerrett</name>
		<title>Director, Marketing</title>
		<image>../../images/ian.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[ Ian takes care of the marketing activities at the Eclipse Foundation.  
			Although our community is the Eclipse marketing machine,  Ian supports the projects and member 
			companies to increase the awareness of all the cool stuff happening at Eclipse.  
			You can read his blog at <a href="http://ianskerrett.wordpress.com/" target="blank">http://ianskerrett.wordpress.com/</a>.
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>
	
	<staffmember id="donald">
		<name>Donald Smith</name>
		<title>Director, Ecosystem Development</title>
		<image> ../../images/donald.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[ 
			After a very busy 2005 completing an MBA, designing a new house and getting 
			married, Donald joined Eclipse to begin 2006 with his now seemingly infinite 
			free time.  Donald has over a decade of experience with enterprise software 
			including product management, marketing, engineering and consulting.  He has 
			spoken on various topics at most major Java conferences including Java One, 
			TSSS, JAOO, CSS, Sun Tech Days and others.  Donald's role at Eclipse is to 
			help foster the development of the ecosystem.
			<br/> &nbsp; <br/> 
			You can read Donald's blog at <a href="http://eclipse-ecosystem.blogspot.com/" target="blank">
			http://eclipse-ecosystem.blogspot.com/</a>.
			]]> 
		</description>
	</staffmember>

	<staffmember id="matt">
		<name>Matt Ward</name>
		<title>Systems Administrator</title>
		<image> ../../images/mattfire.jpg </image>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[ Matt spends his days putting out fires, so afterwards he tends to 
			start them in the kitchen.  And as a change of pace from rebuilding data, there's always 
			rebuilding old cars.
			&nbsp; <br/> &nbsp; <br/>
			]]>
		</description>
	</staffmember>


	<staffmember id="sharon">
		<name>Sharon Wolfe</name>
		<title>Office Manager</title>
		<image> ../../images/sharon.jpg </image>
		<description>
			Sharon has been with the Eclipse Foundation since July 2004.  In addition 
			to her Office Manager responsibilities, Sharon assists with marketing activities and also 
			organizes or assists with the planning of various meetings and conferences.  Sharon thanks 
			Mike every day for opening a proper office because she was going stir crazy working out 
			of the home office in her basement!
		</description>
	</staffmember>
	
</staffmembers>