<boardmember id="hlewis" type="addin">
	<name>Howard Lewis</name>
	<title> <![CDATA[ 
		Advisor/Board Member SlickEdit Inc.
		<br/>
		President & CEO Discovery Machine Inc.
	]]> </title>
	<image>hlewis.jpg</image>
	<email> hlewis@discoverymachine.com </email>
	<phone> 919-819-4310 </phone>
	<contact> <![CDATA[
		Discovery Machine, Inc.<br/>
		454 Pine Street<br/>
		Suite 1A<br/>
		Williamsport, PA,<br/>
		USA 17701<br/>
	]]> </contact>
	<eclipse_affiliation> 
		Mr. Lewis is currently the Add-In Provider Representative to the Eclipse Foundation for 
		SlickEdit Inc. and Discovery Machine, Inc. He currently sits on the Board of the Eclipse Foundation 
		and is a member of the Compensation and Membership Committees. He has been an active part of the 
		Eclipse 'movement'for several years. 
		</eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision>  <![CDATA[
		<p>
		Mr. Lewis remains dedicated to helping make Eclipse THE preeminent open source movement. 
		Preeminent as both the most useful and vibrant open source community and the most widely 
		adopted commercial tool and deployment framework. He will continue to provide special focus 
		on the needs of the Software Development, Knowledge Leverage and Life Sciences domains. He 
		will continue to stay in contact will all members of the Add-in Provider community and 
		actively promote the needs and growth of this key Eclipse Foundation membership body! 
		</p>
		<p>
		Focus Summary:
		<ol>
		<li>Promotion of member joint marketing, sales, and business development initiatives</li>
		<li>Continue to actively promote the adoption of mechanisms/channels to leverage the huge Eclipse pull for members</li>
		<li>Continue to work to align the Eclipse Foundation priorities with the intent of promoting the interests of smaller Add-in Provider companies</li>
		<li>Provide further definition and verification of the prospect of an accepted certification business model</li>
		<li>Focus on Foundation budget priorities to increase member marketing and sales success</li>
		<li>Improve useful and timely communications via newsletters, blogs, email leverage etc.</li>
		<li>Look for opportunities to promote the Foundation in Asia and other under represented geographies</li>
		<li>Look for innovative ways to step-up the pace of deployment on Linux and Mac</li>
		<li>Give proper priority and attention to the Eclipse infrastructure needs of  the Embedded Systems, Application Development, Business Intelligence and Life Sciences domains/vertical business areas  </li>
		</ol>

	]]>	</vision>

	<bio> <![CDATA[
		<p>
		Experience Summary: Mr. Lewis has over 40 years of leadership experience in all facets of 
		software and services companies. He has managed or performed all duties in startups and 
		Fortune 10 companies, alike. Mr. Lewis is currently President and CEO of Discovery Machine, 
		Inc., an Advisor to SlickEdit Inc., Patent Wizards International, and Nevalon Technologies 
		LLC.  Mr. Lewis currently serves on the boards of Discovery Machine, The National Modeling, 
		Simulation, Analysis and Training Coalition, the Eclipse Foundation, and SlickEdit. He also 
		is the Representative for SlickEdit and Discovery Machine in the Eclipse Foundation and the 
		Discovery Machine Representative in the BioSPICE open source community.
		</p>
		<p>Work History/Accomplishments:</p>
		<p>2004-Present</p>
		<p>
		Mr. Lewis is currently President and CEO of Discovery Machine, Inc., an Advisor to SlickEdit 
		Inc., Patent Wizards International, and Nevalon Technologies LLC.  Mr. Lewis currently 
		serves on the boards of Discovery Machine, The National Modeling, Simulation, Analysis and 
		Training Coalition, and SlickEdit. He also is the Add-in Provider Representative for 
		SlickEdit and Discovery Machine in the Eclipse Foundation and the Discovery Machine 
		Representative in the BioSPICE open source community.
		</p>
		<p>2003</p>
		Mr. Lewis joined ePic International, Inc., at the request of the Board of Directors, as 
		President and CEO.  He was charged with leading the stabilization and re-definition of the 
		JV relationships in Asia and Australia, re-doing the PPM and seeking new funding. In 2 
		months he determined that the company was too flawed and too much in debt to continue 
		operation. Mr. Lewis led the task of placing the company into Chapter 7. He has recently 
		completed a consulting engagement for the US bankruptcy court appointed trustee to help 
		bring maximum return to the creditors of ePic International.
		</p>
		<p>2001-2002</p>
		<p>
		Mr. Lewis joined SlickEdit, Inc. as an Advisor and was soon appointed President and COO. At 
		SlickEdit he led the re-branding and re-launch of the company. He helped in creating Sales 
		and Business Development, Marketing and Product Management, and Development and Customer 
		Support positions and supporting processes. He also brought in a top-notch team to fill 
		these roles.
		</p>
		<p>1999-2000</p>
		<p>
		Mr. Lewis joined NxView Technologies, Inc. after leading the pre-funding business case 
		analysis that led to the creation of NxView. He was integral in creating the following 
		positions and recruiting the world-class team to fill these positions.   He held positions 
		as General Manager, Exec VP of Products and Services, Vice President of Research and 
		Technical Strategy, Corporate Client Relations Executive and COO, during the formation and 
		successful launch of NxView. At his retirement he oversaw all research and validation of key 
		technology directions for NxView.
		</p>
		<p>1995-1998</p>
		<p>
		Mr. Lewis joined SEER Technologies, Inc. after completing a comprehensive study of the Seer 
		Methodology and successfully completed Seer's training programs for the Seer•Method and 
		Seer•HPS. While at SEER, Mr. Lewis held the following positions: Sr. Consultant, Sales 
		Consulting Manager, Consulting Director of Eastern North America and retired as VP of 
		Customer Relationships.  He was recognized with the Founders and Top Gun Awards (the only 
		non-sales person to achieve recognition as the top sales leader in the company). He also; 
		Lead the definition and implementation of a company wide Customer Relationship process and 
		was responsible for key customer executive relationships around the world. He also led the 
		definition and start-up of major consulting engagements, in the Transportation, 
		Manufacturing and Services Industries, performing wide-ranging leadership tasks ranging from 
		overall I/T strategy development through engagement management.
		</p>
		<p>1995-Present</p>
		<p>
		Mr. Lewis has acted as an independent consultant since his retirement from IBM. He provides 
		strategic and tactical business development services out of his home offices in Raleigh, NC, 
		Emerald Isle, NC, and Lodi, NY. He dedicates a portion of his efforts as pro bono services 
		to help stimulate not for profit and for profit initiatives, worldwide. He remains dedicated 
		to helping others achieve their deserved success!
		</p>
		<p>1965-1995</p>
		<p>
		Mr. Lewis spent 30 years with IBM in Software Development and Management.  His role as a 
		corporate executive for the Worldwide Software Service Process was defining and implementing 
		the quality process definition and metrics for the IBM Company.  Mr. Lewis represented IBM 
		on Software Quality initiatives at numerous conferences worldwide, including guest lecturing 
		at Motorola University.  He was also responsible for advanced design and strategy for some 
		of the world's largest and most successful operating systems and application development 
		products. He received numerous awards for technology, business and management leadership and 
		was elected President of his IBM Presidents Class. Additionally, Mr. Lewis oversaw the 
		creation and management of strategic relationships for the IBM Application Development and 
		Systems Management businesses. 
		</p>	
	]]>
	</bio>

	<affiliation> <![CDATA[ 
		<b>About SlickEdit, Inc.</b>
		<p>
		SlickEdit Inc. provides software developers with Multilanguage development environments and 
		the most advanced code editors available. Proven on Windows, Linux, UNIX and Mac OS X 
		platforms, SlickEdit products enable even the most accomplished developers to code faster 
		and meet increasingly aggressive deadlines. 
		</p>
		<p>
		SlickEdit's best-of-breed products have created an award winning tradition over its 17-year 
		history. From the numerous customer-based awards such as the Linux World Reader's Choice 
		award and Programmer's Paradise Top Seller awards to the Editor's Choice award from e-Pro 
		Magazine and the Software Development Hall of Fame award, SlickEdit products continually add 
		to and expand on the product foundation of quality, speed, power and flexibility developed 
		years ago by founder and CTO, J. Clark Maurer.
		</p>
		<p>
		Along with producing award-winning products, SlickEdit is considered to be an Employer of 
		Choice and has achieved recognition as one of the Deloitte & Touche Fast 50 technology 
		companies for four consecutive years. SlickEdit is committed to continuing this tradition of 
		excellence.
		</p>
		<p>
		SlickEdit Inc. is a privately held, small business with headquarters in the heart of the 
		renowned Research Triangle, NC.  </p>
	
	]]>
	</affiliation>

		
</boardmember>
