
<boardmember id="mtaylor" type="addin">
	<name> Mike Taylor </name>
	<title> President/CEO Instantiations </title>
	<image>mtaylor.jpg</image>
	<email> mike_taylor@instantiations.com </email>
	<phone> 503 598-4911 </phone>

	<contact> <![CDATA[
		Instantiations, Inc. 18101 <br/>
		S.W. Boones Ferry Rd., Suite 200 <br/>
		Portland, OR 97224 <br/>
		<a href="http://www.instantiations.com/moreaboutmike.htm">...more about Mike</a>
		]]>
	</contact>
	

	<eclipse_affiliation> 
		Since 1999 my professional life has been focused around Eclipse. Building open 
		source and commercial technologies, establishing a profitable Eclipse-based company, and growing the 
		Eclipse community have been my priorities. Instantiations is all Eclipse all the time. 
	</eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision><![CDATA[
		My vision is to:
		<ul>
		<li>Make Eclipse a powerful "profitability platform" for Add-in providers.</li>
		<li>Make the name "Eclipse" a competitive differentiator/advantage similar to "Intel Inside".
		<li>Increase ROI for Add-in Provider membership in the Eclipse Foundation.</li>
		<li>Create an "Eclipse User Council" that brings together key users (not necessarily members) from major 
		industries (i.e. automotive, healthcare, insurance, etc, etc.) to offer suggestions to the Foundation on 
		technology and marketing direction.
		<li>Implement an <a href="http://www.eclipseplugincentral.com">"EPIC-like"</a> portal within eclipse.org that 
		emphasizes Foundation members and gives each a highly visible zone in which to promote their products and 
		services to the community and potential customers.</li>
		<li>and of course, to assure that Eclipse technology remains the best on the planet!</li> 
		</ul> ]]>
	</vision>
		
	<bio><![CDATA[
		<ul>
		<li> Deeply involved in Eclipse technology and ecosystem since 1999</li>
		<li> Former Member of Eclipse Consortium Board of Stewards</li>
		<li> Member of EclipseCon 2006 Program Committee</li>
		<li> Chair of the Eclipse Marketing Committee from 2002-2005</li>
		<li> Lead project to establish Eclipse brand and logos</li>
		<li> Member of Eclipse Market Research Working Group (2005)</li>
		<li> Chair of Eclipse Market Research Working Group (2006)</li>
		<li> Member of Eclipse Governance Committee (that designed and formed the Eclipse Foundation)</li>
		<li> Founding member of <a href="http://www.eclipseplugincentral.com">EPIC</a>, a leading Eclipse portal</li>
		<li> Leads company dedicated to Eclipse. Instantiations has lead eclipse open source projects, 
		contributed code, participated in forming the Foundation and lead numerous Eclipse-focused committees. </li>
		<li> Over 25 years of experience in the software industry.</li>
		</ul> ]]>
	</bio>

	<affiliation><![CDATA[
		<ul>
		<li>Instantiations, Inc, provider of WindowBuilder Pro, SWT Designer, and CodePro Analytix. Instantiations 
		is a technology company totally focused on Eclipse. Instantiations has lead the KOI and Pollinate projects.</li>
		<li>Founding member  of the <a href=" http://www.eclipseplugincentral.com/ContentExpress-display-ceid-2.html">Eclipse Plugin Central Alliance</a>.</li>
		</ul> ]]>
	</affiliation>

</boardmember>