
<boardmember id="twagner" type="committer">

	<type> committer </type>

	<name> Tim Wagner </name>

	<title> Sr. Manager, BEA Workshop </title>

	<image> leave this bkank, but don't forget to send us a picture! </image>

	<email> twagner@bea.com </email>

	<phone> 206.926.2945 </phone>

	<contact> Suite 100, 999 N. Northlake Way, Seattle, WA 98103 </contact>

	<eclipse_affiliation><![CDATA[
	  My primary Eclipse role is in the Web Tools Platform (WTP) Project, where I
	  serve as PMC lead. During my tenure with WTP we've had two major and one minor
	  releases, including our 1.0 ship and first API declarations. My goals for WTP
	  are to ensure a quality platform and highly usable tools, with a short term focus on
	  stability, reliability, and performance. Due to my WTP role, I also
	  evangelize (in print and online forums) for WTP and Eclipse as a whole.
	  
	  I also represent BEA on the Eclipse Architecture and Planning Councils, and am an
	  alternative representative to the Requirements Council. For the upcoming
	  Eclipse Conference in Santa Clara I serve as program chair.]]>
	</eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision> In the course of my work with WTP and BEA, I've been involved in a number
	of issues of concern to committers: services (and service levels) available from
	the Eclipse Foundation infrastructure, IP policies and their application, the
	Eclipse development process, and collaboration within and across Eclipse projects,
	including outreach to developers beyond just those with corporate affiliation.
	I believe there are several topics that require additional attention to continue
	growing and improving the developer and committer community: ensuring that
	contributions from individuals can be effectively absorbed by the projects,
	addressing the "silos" that tend to form around projects (especially the large,
	established ones), and continuing to ensure that we're providing committers with
	all the tools necessary to accomplish their jobs - especially communication and
	build infrastructure. 
	</vision>

	<bio> As a graduate student at UC Berkeley, my PhD research focused on the integration
	of compiler technologies with IDEs. My professional career includes working for Borland, BEA,
	Amazon, and an XQuery-based data integration startup, Nimble Technology. Improving and expanding
	IDE technologies and simplifying the task of authoring complex apps (J2EE and otherwise)
	continues to be a focus of my professional career. I hold a number of patents in the
	areas of IDEs, database integration, and language analysis.
	</bio>

	<affiliation> BEA Systems provides award-winning solutions for application development
	with its WebLogic Platform and a broad range of SOA solutions with its AquaLogic
	products. Within BEA I manage the Workshop team responsible for Eclipse integration
	with WTP and JDT.
	</affiliation>

		
</boardmember>
