<boardmember id="merks" type="committer">

	<name>Ed Merks</name>

	<title>President, Macro Modeling</title>

	<image>merks.jpg</image>

	<email>Ed.Merks@gmail.com</email>

	<eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[		
		Eclipse Modeling Project Lead<br>
		Eclipse Modeling Framework Project Lead
	]]> </eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision>  <![CDATA[
		<p>Eclipse has evolved over the years to become something quite different from its inception.  Today 
		it's driven by a vastly more diverse constellation of contributors: large and small commercial 
		interests, educational institutions, and of course an ever growing dedicated committer community, 
		i.e., people like you and me.  With this increasing diversity, our influence as individuals grows 
		unabated, presenting new challenges and exciting opportunities.  As your committer representative 
		on the board, I will employ my five years of experience to  continue promoting the rights and 
		privileges of committers and to fight for the issues and concerns near and dear to developers' 
		hearts.  As always, I intend to be a visible and approachable technical representative, who 
		navigates the political landscape on your behalf.  I feel I've demonstrated this with my track 
		record over the years.</p>
<p>No doubt it sounds cliche, but I believe strongly that helping is its own reward. With many thousands 
of answers to questions across a wide range of Eclipse's newsgroups last year, and with active blogging 
to promote a sense of community, my track record  is demonstrated with deeds not merely with words. I 
believe in being a positive influence, of balancing the drive to fix problems and to make improvements 
with recognition of the fact that real problems are difficult to solve and that what constitutes 
improvement is often highly subjective.  A case in point is the issue of one committer one vote which 
required a change to the by-laws that was approved by the membership last year.  Not everyone agrees 
this is an improvement, but I'm quite sure the vast majority of the committers will feel their vote 
this year is more influential than ever.</p>
<p>I will continue to work hard to ensure that Eclipse's processes are the best they can be and a
re ever improving. I believe in minimal processes that focus on best practices and achievable 
realistic results. I oppose restrictions that seek to coerce compliance to arbitrary questionable 
rules, particularly rules that are primarily designed to exclude certain groups or to make first 
and second class citizens in our community.  I can be counted upon as the person who will speak up 
diplomatically even when personal risk is involved.  As your representative I commit to working 
tirelessly to promote not only Eclipse itself but also the community that drives it.  It has been an 
honor and a privilege to serve as your representative these past years. If reelected, you can count on 
the fact that Merks works for you.</p>

	]]> </vision>

	<bio> <![CDATA[
		Ed Merks founded his own small consulting company, <a href="http://www.macromodeling.com/" target="blank">Macro Modeling</a>. He 
		is a coauthor of the authoritative book "<a href="http://www.informit.com/store/product.aspx?isbn=9780321331885" 
		target="blank">EMF: Eclipse Modeling Framework</a>" which is published as a second expanded edition. He has been 
		an elected member of the <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/org/foundation/directors.php" target="blank">Eclipse Foundation 
		Board of Directors</a> for the past four years and has been recognized by the Eclipse Community Awards as 
		Top New Comer Evangelist, Top Ambassador, and Top Committer. Ed is well known for his dedication to the 
		Eclipse community, posting literally thousands of newsgroup answers each year. He spent 16 years at IBM, 
		achieving the level of Senior Technical Staff Member after completing his Ph.D. at Simon Fraser University. He is a 
		partner of <a href="http://www.itemis.com/" target="blank">itemis AG</a> and is currently living in Berlin. His 
		experience in modeling technology spans twenty-seven years.
	]]> </bio>

	<affiliation> <![CDATA[ 
		<a href="http://www.macromodeling.com/" target="blank">Macro Modeling</a>, President<br>
		<a href="http://www.itemis.com/" target="blank">itemis AG</a>, Partner
	]]>
	</affiliation>
		
</boardmember>