<boardmember id="wagenknecht" type="committer">

	<name>Gunnar Wagenknecht</name>

	<title>CTO, AGETO</title>

	<image>wagenknecht.jpg</image>

	<email>gunnar@wagenknecht.org</email>

	<eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[
<a href="http://planeteclipse.org/planet/">Planet Eclipse</a> Creator<br/>
<a href="http://www.eclipse.org/technology/">Technology</a> PMC Lead<br/>
<a href="http://www.eclipse.org/gyrex/">Gyrex</a> Lead<br/>
Committer on Gyrex, Orbit, RAP Incubator<br/>
Contributor to Equinox, EclipseLink, Gemini and PDE<br/>
Architecture Council member<br/>
<a href="http://www.eclipsecon.org/">EclipseCon</a> Program Committee (2006, 2012)

	]]> </eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision>  <![CDATA[

<p>
Eclipse is an exceptional community. In my opinion the most important
piece of this community is a vivid and steady flow of manifold
contributions coming from committers, member companies, adopters and
users. I'm a strong supporter of the Eclipse community, it's openness
and diversity across the board. When initiating Planet Eclipse back in
2005 it wasn't just to raise the voice of the Eclipse community on the
web but also to give community members a chance to raise their voice to
be heard within the community.
</p><p>
My vision for 2012 is to ensure that the committer interests are
properly represented at the Eclipse Board meetings. I intend to actively
participate in ongoing as well as to initiate new discussions on topics
which aid improving the life and work of committers and contributors at
Eclipse projects.
</p><p>
Another important part of my work will be to ensure that enough funding
is available to provide first-class infrastructure services to
committers around the globe. With Git and Gerrit coming to Eclipse projects 
there is a new door open for contributions. I'll strive for simplifying the 
processes to lower the barrier for new contributors further. I also like to 
initiate discussions about interesting tools that might help Eclipse projects 
running more smoothly.
</p>



	]]> </vision>

	<bio> <![CDATA[
Gunnar is a software engineer who loves server and application 
architectures especially those involving Equinox/OSGi. In his primary 
role at AGETO he is thrilled to work on open source software, emerging 
platforms and technologies, and to help companies understand Eclipse and 
OSGi and execute on their business objectives in an open source context. 
He has been a member of the Eclipse Community since its beginning and 
he is a prolific contributor with many years of experience on numerous 
Eclipse projects; Gunnar leads the Technology PMC and is a member of the 
Eclipse Architecture Council. Apart from Eclipse he loves chatting about 
fishing, diving and his family and other things that matters over a good 
beer or a glass of dry, barrel aged red wine. 
	]]> </bio>

	<affiliation> <![CDATA[ 
	AGETO, Jena, Germany
	]]>
	</affiliation>

		
</boardmember>
