<boardmember id="aniszczyk" type="committer">

	<name>Chris Aniszczyk</name>

	<title>Engineering Manager, Open Source (Twitter)</title>

	<image>aniszczyk.jpg</image>

	<email>zx@twitter.com</email>

	<eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[		
        <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/technology/team-leaders.php">Technology</a> and Mylyn PMC Member<br>
        <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/egit">EGit</a> / JGit Committer<br>
        <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/orbit">Orbit</a> Committer<br>               
        <a href="http://planet.eclipse.org">PlanetEclipse.org</a> Maintainer<br> 
        <a href="http://www.eclipsecon.org">EclipseCon</a> Program Committee (2007-2012)<br> 
        Eclipse Board Committer Representative (2007-2012)
	]]> </eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision>  <![CDATA[
		<p>My overall vision for Eclipse is simple, keep building the <b>community</b> so the Eclipse ecosystem can prosper. 
		We have a unique open source community at Eclipse that is comprised of a variety of parties, from individuals to 
		academics to companies. We need to keep all parties in mind, whether an individual or corporation, and make it 
		easier for everyone to be successful at Eclipse. I think this is especially important given that the Eclipse Foundation
                is expanding with efforts such as <a href="http://locationtech.org/">LocationTech</a>. 
                </p>
		
		<p>Eclipse has been around for just over a decade. We have to keep moving forward to stay relevant in a sea of 
		technological change. In the last year, we have done great things like 
		move to <a href="http://mmilinkov.wordpress.com/2012/12/21/eclipse-says-goodbye-to-cvs/">Git/Gerrit</a> (which I'm proud to have 
		helped initiate a couple years ago) and started pushing the boundaries of web tooling with 
		the <a href="http://planetorion.org/news/2012/10/orion-1-0-release/">Orion 1.0 release</a>. However, there are 
		many more things we can do to move things forward. <b>My main focus will be to push for a system where we can 
		leverage social coding sites (such as GitHub or Google Code) while maintaining our reputation for a quality development 
		process and rigorous IP management.</b> This would allow us to grow as a community while taking advantage of all the 
		innovation that has happened in the social coding andy infrastructure space recently. It would also make the the Eclipse Foundation 
		more adaptable to infrastructure changes in the future, further hone our development process and ensure that we're ready for 
		another successful decade of changing the industry.</p>

		<p>To ensure Eclipse continues to grow and thrive I will particularly focus on:</p>
		
		<ul>
			<li>Push the Foundation to allow hosting projects on GitHub and other social coding sites</li>
                        <li>Make it easier to accept contributions from GitHub and Bitbucket</li>
			<li>Foster interactions with the web development community and Orion</li>
			<li>Build bridges within the Eclipse ecosystem and with other open source and commercial projects</li>
			<li>Encourage Eclipse committers and projects to participate in the community via blogs, forums and other communication channels</li>
			<li>Lower the barrier to entry for new projects without sacrificing the quality Eclipse is known for</li>
			<li>Ensure Eclipse processes are transparent and lightweight as possible</li>
		</ul>
		
		<p>On the whole, my goal is to make Eclipse thrive and be transparent as possible about the board's 
		activities. I love bringing new projects to the Eclipse ecosystem and mentoring new committers. I will pay 
		special attention to how we can make the Eclipse development process easier for smaller projects. In the end, 
		I would be honored to represent you, the committers, for another term.</p>		
		]]> </vision>

	<bio> <![CDATA[
		<p>
		Chris Aniszczyk (<a href="http://twitter.com/cra">@cra</a>) is a software architect by trade with a 
		passion for open source and building communities. At Twitter, he's responsible for 
		creating their open source program and managing their open source efforts. He also has the honor 
		to sit on the Eclipse Architecture and Planning councils. In a previous life, he traveled the world and 
		consulted companies on Eclipse technology. He also lead and hacked on many eclipse.org and linux related 
		projects. In his spare time, you'll find him running, cycling or doing yoga.</p>		
	]]> </bio>

	<affiliation> <![CDATA[ 
		Twitter
	]]>
	</affiliation>
		
</boardmember>