<boardmember id="lewis" type="addin">

<name>Howard H. Lewis</name>

<title>Advisor/Board Member, SlickEdit Inc.; President and CEO, 
Discovery Machine Inc.</title>

<image>lewis.jpg </image>

<email>hlewis@slickedit.com </email> 
<email>hlewis@discoverymachine.com</email>

<phone>919.819.4310</phone>

<contact> <![CDATA[
SlickEdit, Inc.<br>
3000 Aerial Center Pkwy <br>
Suite 120 <br>
Morrisville, NC 27560<br>
]]> </contact>

<eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[
<p>Mr. Lewis is currently the Add-In Provider Representative to the Eclipse Foundation for SlickEdit Inc. and Discovery
Machine, Inc. He currently sits on the Board of the Eclipse Foundation and is a member of the 
Compensation and Membership Committies and an EPIC Project Committer. He has been an active part of the Eclipse 'movement'
for several years. </p>
]]> </eclipse_affiliation>

<vision> <![CDATA[	
<p>Mr. Lewis remains dedicated to helping make Eclipse THE preeminent open source movement.
 Preeminent as both the most useful and vibrant open source community and the most widely
  addopted commercial and non-commercial tool and RPC based deployment framework. 
  He will continue to provide special focus on the needs of the Software Development, Knowledge Leverage and Life Sciences domains. He will continue to stay in contact will all members of the Add-in Provider community and actively promote the needs and growth of this key Eclipse Foundation membership body! </p>
<p>Focus Summary:</p>
<ol>
<li>Promotion of member joint marketing, sales, and business development initiatives</li>
<li>Continue to actively promote the adoption of mechanisms/channels to leverage the huge Eclipse pull for members; with a specific focus on EPIC related opportunities</li>
<li>Continue to work to align the Eclipse Foundation priorities with the intent of promoting the interests of smaller Add-in Provider companies</li>
<li>Provide further definition and verification of a very well accepted and very high quality business model</li>
<li>Focus on Foundation budget priorities to increase member marketing and sales success</li>
<li>Improve useful and timely communications via newsletters, blogs, email leverage etc.</li>
<li>Look for opportunities to promote the Foundation in all under represented geographies</li>
<li>Look for innovative ways to step-up the pace of deployment on Linux and Mac</li>
<li>Give proper priority and attention to the Eclipse infrastructure needs of  the Embedded Systems, Application Development, Business Intelligence and Life Sciences domains/vertical business areas</li>
</ol>
]]> </vision>  

<bio> <![CDATA[
<p>Experience Summary:</p>
<p>Mr. Lewis has over 40 years of leadership experience in all facets of software and 
services companies. He has managed or performed all duties in startups and 
Fortune 10 companies, alike. Mr. Lewis is currently President and CEO of Discovery Machine, Inc., an 
Advisor to SlickEdit Inc., and Nevalon Technologies LLC.  Mr. Lewis currently serves on the boards of Discovery Machine, 
the Eclipse Foundation, and SlickEdit. He also is the Representative for SlickEdit and Discovery Machine in the Eclipse Foundation and the Discovery Machine Representative in the BioSPICE open source community.</p>

<p>Work History/Accomplishments:</p>
<p>2004-Present</p>

<p>Mr. Lewis is currently President and CEO of Discovery Machine, Inc., 
an Advisor to SlickEdit Inc., and Nevalon Technologies LLC.  
Mr. Lewis currently serves on the boards of Discovery Machine and SlickEdit. 
He also is the Add-in Provider Representative for SlickEdit and Discovery Machine 
in the Eclipse Foundation and the Discovery Machine Representative in the BioSPICE open source community.</p>

<p>2003</p>

<p>Mr. Lewis joined ePic International, Inc., at the request of the Board of Directors, as President and CEO.  He was charged with leading the stabilization and re-definition of the JV relationships in Asia and Australia, re-doing the PPM and seeking new funding. In 2 months he determined that the company was too flawed and too much in debt to continue operation. Mr. Lewis led the task of placing the company into Chapter 7. He has recently completed a consulting engagement for the US bankruptcy court appointed trustee to help bring maximum return to the creditors of ePic International.</p>

<p>2001-2002</p>

<p>Mr. Lewis joined SlickEdit, Inc. as an Advisor and was soon appointed President and COO. At SlickEdit he led the re-branding and re-launch of the company. He helped in creating Sales and Business Development, Marketing and Product Management, and Development and Customer Support positions and supporting processes. He also brought in a top-notch team to fill these roles.</p>

<p>1999-2000</p>

<p>Mr. Lewis joined NxView Technologies, Inc. after leading the pre-funding business case analysis that led to the creation of NxView. He was integral in creating the following positions and recruiting the world-class team to fill these positions.   He held positions as General Manager, Exec VP of Products and Services, Vice President of Research and Technical Strategy, Corporate Client Relations Executive and COO, during the formation and successful launch of NxView. At his retirement he oversaw all research and validation of key technology directions for NxView.</p>

<p>1995-1998</p>

<p>Mr. Lewis joined SEER Technologies, Inc. after completing a comprehensive study of the Seer Methodology and successfully 
completed Seer's training programs for the SeeriMethod and SeeriHPS. While at SEER, Mr. Lewis held the following positions: Sr. Consultant, Sales Consulting Manager, Consulting Director of Eastern North America and retired as VP of Customer Relationships.  He was recognized with the Founders and Top Gun Awards (the only non-sales person to achieve recognition as the top sales leader in the company). He also; Lead the definition and implementation of a company wide Customer Relationship process and was responsible for key customer executive relationships around the world. He also led the definition and start-up of major consulting engagements, in the Transportation, Manufacturing and Services Industries, performing wide-ranging leadership tasks ranging from overall I/T strategy development through engagement management.</p>

<p>1995-Present</p>

<p>Mr. Lewis has acted as an independent consultant since his retirement from IBM. He provides strategic and tactical business development services out of his home offices in Raleigh, NC, Emerald Isle, NC, and Lodi, NY. He dedicates a portion of his efforts as pro bono services to help stimulate not for profit and for profit initiatives, worldwide. He remains dedicated to helping others achieve their deserved success!</p>

<p>1965-1995</p>

<p>Mr. Lewis spent 30 years with IBM in Software Development and Management.  His role as a corporate executive for the Worldwide Software Service Process was defining and implementing the quality process definition and metrics for the IBM Company.  Mr. Lewis represented IBM on Software Quality initiatives at numerous conferences worldwide, including guest lecturing at Motorola University.  He was also responsible for advanced design and strategy for some of the world's largest and most successful operating systems and application development products. He received numerous awards for technology, business and management leadership and was elected President of his IBM Presidents Class. Additionally, Mr. Lewis oversaw the creation and management of strategic relationships for the IBM Application Development and Systems Management businesses.</p>

]]> </bio> 

<affiliation> <![CDATA[ 

<p>About SlickEdit Inc.</p>

<p>SlickEdit Inc. provides software developers with multilanguage development environments and the most advanced code editors 
available. Proven on Windows, Linux, UNIX and Mac OS X platforms, SlickEdit products enable even the most accomplished 
developers to code faster and meet increasingly aggressive deadlines.</p> 

<p>SlickEdit's best-of-breed products have created an award winning tradition over its 17-year history. From the numerous 
customer-based awards such as the Linux World Reader's Choice award and Programmer's Paradise Top Seller awards to the 
Editor's Choice award from e-Pro Magazine and the Software Development Hall of Fame award, SlickEdit products continually 
add to and expand on the product foundation of quality, speed, power and flexibility developed years ago by founder and CTO, J. Clark Maurer.</p>

<p>Along with producing award-winning products, SlickEdit is considered to be an Employer of Choice and has achieved 
recognition as one of the Deloitte & Touche Fast 50 technology companies for four consecutive years. SlickEdit is committed to 
continuing this tradition of excellence.</p>

<p>SlickEdit Inc. is a privately held, small business with headquarters in the heart of the renowned Research Triangle, NC.</p>  

<p>About Discovery Machine, Inc.</p>

<p>Solving the fundamental challenges of knowledge leverage and human behavior modeling:</p>
 
<p>Founded in 1999, Discovery Machine Inc. immediately gained success for it's revolutionary approach to 
knowledge acquisition and engineering. DMI is focused on making the transfer of knowledge easily accessible to non-technical experts.</p> 

<p>DMI provides custom solutions, software tools, comprehensive services and training to a broad range of 
industries that include national defense, homeland security, aerospace, manufacturing, and life sciences.</p> 

<p>Discovery Machine Inc. is a privately held, woman owned, small business with headquarters in Williamsport, PA., and 
offices in Raleigh, N.C.</p> 
]]> </affiliation>
		
</boardmember>
