<boardmember id="taylor" type="addin">

<name> Mike Taylor </name>

<title> President/CEO Instantiations </title>

<image> taylor.jpg </image>

<email> mike_taylor@instantiations.com </email>

<phone> 503 598-4911 </phone>

<contact> <![CDATA[<a 
href="http://www.instantiations.com/moreaboutmike.htm">Click here to 
learn about Mike</a>.]]> </contact>

<eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[
<p>As one of your current Add-in Provider 
(AIP) Board members I strongly supported the interests of our 
community in 2006 and would be honored to represent you again in 
2007. Over the past year I've been actively involved in transitioning 
EPIC (Eclipse Plugin Central) from private ownership to the Eclipse 
Foundation, resulting in a significant increase in visibility for 
Eclipse-based commercial and open source plugins. </p>
<p>I also chaired 
Eclipse's Market Research and Training Research Working Groups, and 
actively participated in a range of Eclipse Foundation and community 
activities. Since 1999 my professional priorities have been, and 
continue to be, building open source and commercial technologies, 
establishing a profitable Eclipse-based company, and growing the 
Eclipse community. <i>Instantiations is all Eclipse all the time.</i></p> 
]]></eclipse_affiliation>

<vision> <![CDATA[<p>My vision for 2007 is to:</p><ul>
<li>Show up, speak up, and stand up for the interests of AIP members 
at Eclipse Board meetings during 2007.</li>
<li>Continue to increase ROI for Add-in Provider membership in the 
Eclipse Foundation.</li>
<li>Continue the evolution of EPIC (Eclipse Plugin Central) as the 
key portal for Eclipse Plug-ins and Services.</li>
<li>Make Eclipse a powerful "profitability platform" for Add-in providers.</li>
<li>...and of course, to assure that Eclipse technology remains the 
best on the planet!</li>
</ul>]]> </vision>

<bio> <![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Lead Instantiations, a company strategically committed to 
Eclipse. Instantiations is a founding member of the Eclipse 
Foundation, has led Eclipse open source projects, contributed code, 
and is involved in numerous Eclipse-focused committees and community 
activities.</li>
<li>Chair of Eclipse Market Research Working Group (2006).</li>
<li>Chair of the Eclipse Training Working Group (2006).</li>
<li>Member of EclipseCon 2006 Program Committee.</li>
<li>Deeply involved in Eclipse technology and ecosystem since 1999.</li>
<li>Former Member of Eclipse Consortium Board of Stewards.</li>
<li>Chair of the Eclipse Marketing Committee from 2002 to 2005.</li>
<li>Led project to establish Eclipse brand and logos.</li>
<li>Member of Eclipse Governance Committee (that designed and formed 
the Eclipse Foundation).</li>
<li>Founding member of <a 
href="http://www.eclipseplugincentral.com">EPIC</a>, a leading 
Eclipse portal.</li>
<li>Over 25 years of experience in the software industry.</li>
</ul>]]> </bio>

<affiliation> <![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Instantiations, Inc, provider of WindowBuilder Pro, RCP 
Developer, CodePro AnalytiX and GWT Designer. Instantiations is a 
technology company totally focused on Eclipse. Instantiations has led 
and contributed to several Eclipse open source projects and is deeply 
involved in the Eclipse community.</li>
<li>Founding member of the <a 
href="http://www.eclipseplugincentral.com/ContentExpress-display-ceid-2.html">Eclipse 
Plugin Central Alliance</a>.</li>
</ul>]]> </affiliation>

</boardmember>