<boardmember id="wagenknecht" type="committer">

	<name>Gunnar Wagenknecht</name>

	<title>Chief Architect, AGETO</title>

	<image>wagenknecht.jpg</image>

	<email>gunnar@wagenknecht.org</email>

	<eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[
		Planet Eclipse Creator<br>
		Technology PMC Member<br>
		Gyrex Lead<br>
		Orbit Committer<br>
		RAP Incubator Committer<br>
		Architecture Council member<br>
		EclipseCon Program Committee (2006)	
	]]> </eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision>  <![CDATA[
		Eclipse is an exceptional community. In my opinion the most important
		piece of this community is a vivid and steady flow of manifold
		contributions coming from member companies, committers, adopters and
		users. I'm a strong supporter of the Eclipse community, it's openness
		and diversity across the board. When initiating Planet Eclipse back in
		2005 it wasn't just to raise the voice of the Eclipse community on the
		web but also to give community members a chance to raise their voice to
		be heard within the community.
		<br><br>
		My vision for 2011 is to ensure that the committer interests are
		properly represented at the Eclipse Board meetings. I intend to actively
		participate in ongoing as well as to initiate new discussions on topics
		which aid improving the life and work of committers at Eclipse projects.
		<br><br>
		Another important part of my work will be to ensure that enough funding
		is available to provide first-class infrastructure services to
		committers. With Git coming to Eclipse projects there is a new door open
		for contributions. The current processes involving Bugzilla, IPZilla and
		patches need to be reviewed. New tools like Gerrit will come into the
		game and need to be looked at. There is not only the question of
		adopting those tools into the Eclipse Development and IP Process. There
		is also the question of evolving the processes to (better) support new
		workflows offered by these tools.
	]]> </vision>

	<bio> <![CDATA[
		Gunnar is a software engineer who loves server and application
		architectures especially those involving Equinox/OSGi. In his primary
		role at AGETO he is thrilled to work on open source software, emerging
		platforms and technologies, and to help companies understand Eclipse and
		OSGi and execute on their business objectives in an open source context.
		He has been a member of the Eclipse Community since its beginning and he
		is a prolific contributor with many years of experience on numerous
		Eclipse projects; Gunnar is also a member of the Technology PMC which he
		represents on the Eclipse Architecture Council. Apart from Eclipse he
		loves chatting about fishing, diving and his family and other things
		that matters over a good beer or a glass of dry, barrel aged red wine.
	]]> </bio>

	<affiliation> <![CDATA[ 
		AGETO
	]]>
	</affiliation>
		
</boardmember>