
<boardmember id="day" type="addin">

	<name>Robert Day</name>

	<title>VP Marketing</title>

	<image>day.jpg</image>

	<email>rday@lnxw.com</email>

	<phone>(+1) 408-979-3900</phone>

	<contact>
		<![CDATA[
		LynuxWorks<br>
		855 Embedded Way<br>
		San Jose CA 95138<br>
		USA
		]]>
	</contact>

	<eclipse_affiliation>
		<![CDATA[
		LynuxWorks, Add-in Provider<br>
		Chairman, Eclipse embedded workgroup
		]]>
	</eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision> 
		<![CDATA[
		<p>I believe that a common technology can unite many different worlds, and that 
		technology is driven and developed by a community rather than a single entity. 
		It can bring partners and competitors closer together and it can span across many 
		different markets and types of product development. I believe that Eclipse has 
		many characteristics that will allow it to become that single common enabling 
		platform. The huge and growing ecosystem of companies and technologies that 
		surrounds Eclipse, coupled with a business model that allows companies to 
		build and sell better products will continuously evolve and enhance the 
		technology and its applicability to more and more developers.</p>
		
		<p>My world has been that of embedded device development, and I see many 
		synergies between the software development tools from embedded and the 
		enterprise/desktop worlds that could bridge the gap between these two areas. 
		I also see that by using a higher level of abstraction when designing systems, 
		then hardware development and software development could also be more closely 
		united. Eclipse certainly has the flexibility to allow these typically disparate 
		entities to unite making the developers more productive and allowing tool 
		vendors to integrate more effectively. I would like to encourage more 
		collaboration between companies and their technologies that have traditionally 
		been focused in their own domains or markets and to explore new solutions 
		(or Eclipse projects) that will ultimately increase the productivity of 
		developers.</p>
		]]>	
	</vision>

	<bio> 
		<![CDATA[
		<p>I earned a Bachelors degree in Computer Science. My first role was programming 
		SCADA systems (RTL/2 on a PDP-11), and then moved into programming the embedded 
		parts of those systems in assembler and Pascal. I changed career path and worked 
		for Microtec Research, where I developed some of the early versions of the 
		famous XRAY debugger. I found that I enjoyed explaining the technology and 
		products as much as developing them so I moved into a technical sales role, 
		and spent my time explaining compiler optimizations, and demonstrating the 
		first IDE for embedded development (MasterWorks). My career for the last 
		10 years has been marketing, where I help bring new software products to the 
		embedded world. I have been very active in promoting both Eclipse and Eclipse 
		based products with both Mentor Graphics and now LynuxWorks.  I have chaired 
		the Eclipse embedded workgroup for the last 4 years and have been focused on 
		how to bring the embedded software world together under the common standard 
		platform of Eclipse.  I have written many Eclipse articles and papers for 
		embedded publications, and have presented Eclipse papers and chaired Eclipse 
		discussions at the last four Embedded Systems Conferences and EclipseCon 2007.
		</p>
		<p>Articles:<br>
		<a href="http://www.embedded-control-europe.com/know-how?kid=79">Eclilpse as a common IDE</a><br>
		<a href="http://www2.theiet.org/oncomms/sector/electronics/magazine.cfm?issueID=171&articleID=EF43C365-C2FF-4798-336FE1199996A34B">Shared future</a><br> 
		<a href="http://mae.pennnet.com/articles/article_display.cfm?Section=ARTCL&C=Depar&ARTICLE_ID=294940&KEYWORDS=eclipse&p=32">Eclipse: software development environment in the firing line</a><br>
		</p>	 
		]]>
	</bio>

	<affiliation> 
		<![CDATA[
		LynuxWorks
		]]>
	</affiliation>

		
</boardmember>
