
<boardmember id="gaff" type="committer">

	<name>Doug Gaff</name>

	<title>Senior Manager</title>

	<image>gaff.jpg</image>

	<email>doug.gaff@windriver.com</email>

	<phone>781-364-2295</phone>

	<contact>
		<![CDATA[
		Wind River Systems<br>
		350 Terry Fox Drive, Suite 200<br>
		Kanata, ON K2K 2W5<br>
		Canada
		]]>
	</contact>

	<eclipse_affiliation>
		<![CDATA[
		<ul>
		<li>DSDP PMC Lead</li>
		<li>EclipseCon 2008 Program Committee Chair</li>
		<li>Requirements and Architecture Council</li>
		<li>Project Mentor</li>
		<li>IP Process Working Group</li>
		</ul>
		]]>
	</eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision> 
		<![CDATA[
		<p>Eclipse is growing: projects, committers, code base, and ecosystem. Included in that growth is an ever-enlarging 
		Board of Directors. The Board has become diverse enough that Eclipse must now have multiple distinct strategies for 
		continued relevance in both the open source and commercial venues. The Board seems to be struggling to respond to this 
		reality, and there's never been a better time to get involved!</p>
		
		<p>My vision for Eclipse and my role on the Board break down into two facets:</p>
	<ul>
	<li>Responding to Growth</li>
		<ul>
		<li>Focus on Technical Verticals that move beyond the Enterprise.</li>
		<li>Recruiting companies to sponsor projects rather than\'a0 just use them.</li>
		<li>Focus on streamlining the Development IP Due Diligence processes.</li>
		</ul>
	<li>Defining the Role of the Board</li>
		<ul>
		<li>Ensure the committer and user community needs are represented and perceived as relevant.</li>
		<li>Facilitate discussions about the balance between doing good for the user community and doing good for commercial adopters.</li>
		<li>Increase the role of the Board and Foundation in describing and evangelizing Eclipse-based commercial business models.</li>
		</ul>
 	</ul>
		]]>	
	</vision>

	<bio> 
		<![CDATA[
		<p>In his open source life, Doug Gaff is the PMC Lead for the Device Software Development Platform (DSDP) - an Eclipse project 
		focused on building an extensible, standards-based platform to address a broad range of needs in the embedded and mobile 
		software development space. Doug is also the Technical Program Chair for EclipseCon 08. In his commercial life, Doug is a 
		Senior Engineering Manager on Wind River's commercial Eclipse-based product, Wind River Workbench. He is responsible for 
		Eclipse open source contributions and adoption of Eclipse technology commercially. Doug has 13 years of embedded software 
		development experience and holds a Bachelors and Masters in Electrical Engineering.</p>	 
		]]>
	</bio>

	<affiliation> 
		<![CDATA[
		Wind River Systems
		]]>
	</affiliation>

		
</boardmember>
