<boardmember id="komissarchik" type="committer">

  <name>
    Konstantin Komissarchik
  </name>

  <title>
  </title>

  <image>komissarchik.jpg
  </image>

  <email>
    kosta@bea.com
  </email>

  <phone>
    206.926.2962
  </phone>

  <contact> <![CDATA[
BEA Systems, Inc.<br>
999 North Northlake Way<br>
Seattle, WA 98103<br>
USA<br>
  ]]> </contact>

  <eclipse_affiliation>
    Web Tools Platform
  </eclipse_affiliation>

  <vision> <![CDATA[
    I am a committer on the Web Tools project and a team lead
    at BEA working on a product with close ties to Eclipse. I am also currently serving as an elected 
    Committer Representative and I am running for re-election this year. I am running again because a lot of 
    work remains to be done to accomplish the goals that I set out for myself when I ran for this position 
    last year. I am passionate about bringing committers from different projects together and enabling them 
    to be collaborate in creating a cohesive user experience rather than the silo effect that is so evident 
    in Eclipse today. There are many aspects or reasons for the situation that we find ourselves in today. Some 
    of them are social. Some of them are infrastructural. It is the second one where I think the Eclipse Foundation 
    can make the biggest difference. Imagine if there was a way to easily create micro-components for projects to 
    collaborate on a feature or two. Imagine if build was a service provided by the foundation (just like CVS) and 
    every project didn’t have to struggle with this on their own. Some progress has been made, but there is a lot more 
    work still left to do. If you vote for me, I promise to keep pushing to break down the silos.</p>
 
	<p>Those who are interested in learning more about one aspect of what I am trying to accomplish should 
	visit http://wiki.eclipse.org/Nexus_Project.</p>
  ]]> </vision>
 
  <bio>
    I am a software developer with BEA Systems and have been a committer on the
    Web Tools Platform since its first release. I have designed and implemented
    the Faceted Project Framework which made it possible for people to easily
    extend capabilities of WTP projects. In my prior life, I have worked on 
    compilers, custom servers and network protocol design. I have graduated from 
    the University of Washington with BS in Computer Science.
  </bio>

  <affiliation>
    BEA Systems, Inc.
  </affiliation>	
</boardmember>