<boardmember id="komissarchik" type="committer">

  <name>
    Konstantin Komissarchik
  </name>

  <title>
  Staff Software Engineer
  </title>

  <image>komissarchik.jpg
  </image>

  <email>
    kosta@bea.com
  </email>

  <phone>
    206.926.2962
  </phone>

  <contact> <![CDATA[
BEA Systems, Inc.<br>
999 North Northlake Way<br>
Seattle, WA 98103<br>
USA<br>
  ]]> </contact>

  <eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[
    Web Tools Platform committer<br>
	Web Tools Common Project lead<br>
	Eclipse Foundation Board of Directors Committer Representative (2007-2008)
  ]]> </eclipse_affiliation>

  <vision> <![CDATA[
    <p>The last year has gone by very quickly. It has been an honor and privilege to 
    represent the committers to Eclipse Foundation’s Board of Directors. During the 
    course of the year, I pushed on a variety of fronts to make sure that the 
    foundation is effectively serving committers and protecting their investment. I 
    am active in the ongoing discussions to improve the IP Process. I have also been 
    involved in defining a way to bring tasteful advertisement to eclipse.org as a 
    way to improve member value and make sure that Foundation continues to be fully 
    funded and is able to serve committers effectively.</p>
 
	<p>When I ran for this position last year, I set some specific goals for myself. 
	While some progress has been made, a lot of work still remains. I am passionate 
	about bringing committers from different projects together and enabling them to 
	collaborate in creating a cohesive user experience rather than the silo effect 
	that is so evident in Eclipse today. There are many aspects or reasons for the 
	situation that we find ourselves in today. Some of them are social. Some of them 
	are infrastructural. It is the second one where I think the Eclipse Foundation 
	can make the biggest difference. Imagine if there was a way to easily create 
	micro-components for projects to collaborate on a feature or two. Imagine if 
	build was a service provided by the foundation (just like CVS) and every project 
	didn't have to struggle with this on their own. Some progress has been made, but 
	there is a lot more work still left to do. You can visit 
	<a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/Nexus_Project">http://wiki.eclipse.org/Nexus_Project</a> to 
	get more information about one aspect of my efforts in this area.</p>
  ]]> </vision>
 
  <bio> <![CDATA[
    <p>Konstantin is an engineering team lead at BEA Systems working on a product with 
    close ties to Eclipse and has been a committer on the Web Tools Platform since 
    before its first release. He has designed and implemented the Faceted Project 
    Framework which made it possible for people to easily extend capabilities of WTP 
    projects. In his prior life, he has worked on compilers, custom servers and network 
    protocol design. He graduated from the University of Washington with BS in 
    Computer Science.</p>
  ]]>  </bio>

  <affiliation>
    BEA Systems, Inc.
  </affiliation>	
</boardmember>