<boardmember id="ragan" type="addin">

	<name>Tracy Ragan</name>

	<title>Chief Operating Officer</title>

	<image>ragan.jpg</image>

	<email>tracy.ragan@openmakesoftware.com</email>

	<phone>505-424-6440</phone>

	<contact> <![CDATA[
Openmake Software<br>
213 W. Institute Place #404<br>
Chicago, IL 60010<br>
www.openmakesoftware.com ]]> </contact>

	<eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[
	Involvement with Eclipse has become a substantial part of my background and experience. I have
	been involved with Eclipse in some capacity since 2002 when  I started hearing about the "Eclipse Project". At
	that time,  I took a closer look at Eclipse and was immediately surprised by what I found, an open source effort 
	focused around a common IDE platform. By the end of 2002, I had become a "founding steward" of this new
	and exciting community.  I've watched the Eclipse organization grow and change, always adding my "2 cents" along the way.<br>
	  
	<p>During 2007 I have had the pleasure of serving on the Eclipse board representing the Eclipse Eco-system of
	 Add-in Providers.  It is my belief that the Add-in Provider community is and will continue to be the core of 
	 Eclipse.  Even though our strategic members our important, it is the Add-in providers who bring a well rounded commercial 
	 market based on the Eclipse technology.</p>

	<vision> <![CDATA[
    <p>Involvement from Add-in Provider companies is a critical component of the overall success of 
    Eclipse.  Some Add-in Providers have learned how to stay involved even as Eclipse has grown.  I 
    believe there are many more Add-in Providers who want to be active, not passive, members of 
    Eclipse but simply don't know how. Add-in Providers need to be better organized so that they can 
    more easily see how to get involved.  In addition, Add-in providers need to be recognized as a 
    core pillar of Eclipse.  This can be done through better recognition programs for active Add-in 
    Providers and an increased focus on Add-in Providers through Public Relations contacts.  Add-in 
    Provider contribution is important.  What we don't want is for the Eclipse organization to evolve 
    to a place where Add-in Providers simply serve as an audience to the Strategic Members.  We are 
    the "members at large" and represent one of the core pillars of this organization.</p>
       		
	]]> </vision>

	<bio> <![CDATA[
	<p>I  have served as both CEO and COO for OpenMake Software since 1995.  I started my IT career as a 
	mainframe programmer in the mid 1980s and moved into C programming mainly in OS/2 PM by the late 1980s.  I worked 
	as an independent consultant for 8 years before forming OpenMake Software with my partner Steve Taylor.  Since that 
	time we have created the now emerging market of enterprise build management tools with Openmake Meister the leader and 
	most complete solution available.  We have done this without any level of VC funding by letting our superior 
	software fund itself.  The experience of growing OpenMake Software will be extremely valuable when is comes to 
	serving as a member of the Eclipse Board.  </p>
	]]> </bio>

	<affiliation> <![CDATA[
	<p>OpenMake Software is the leading vendor of Enterprise Build Management Solutions.  OpenMake Meister, our 
	flagship product, was launched in June of 1995.  Since that time OpenMake Software has revolutionized 
	the way developers manage their build process by mashing up the individual developer's IDE builds with 
	the team build executed outside of the IDE. OpenMake Software enjoys close partnerships with other Eclipse 
	Members such as Serena Software, Computer Associates, MKS Inc., and IBM.</p>
	]]> </affiliation>
		
</boardmember>