<boardmember id="brede" type="addin">

	<name>Hans-Joachim Brede</name>

	<title>CEO, Bredex</title>

	<image>brede.jpg</image>

	<email>hans-joachim.brede@bredex.de</email>

	<eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[ <p>
Bredex GmbH joined the Eclipse Foundation as a Solutions Member in 2007. As well as 
using Eclipse as an IDE, we also offer RCP training. Members of Bredex have 
worked as contributors and committers on Eclipse projects. </p>
		
	]]> </eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision> <![CDATA[ <p>
Having spent 2009 establishing a good level of contact and communication between European and American
members, as well as learning about the structures and methods of the Eclipse Board and Foundation, I see
2010 as the chance to expand and improve these contacts to pull the European and American communities
even closer together.</p>
<p>2009 has also seen Eclipse take steps in the direction of vertical industries. While fully supporting
this move, I see myself as a representative of the Eclipse community using and committing to the core
technology of the platform, to ensure that the further development of Eclipse profits from the views of
both groups.</p>
	]]> </vision>

	<bio> <![CDATA[ <p>
Hans-Joachim (Achim) Brede is the founder of BREDEX GmbH and is one of its 
managing directors. He has implemented and managed multiple, highly complex 
customer projects and is responsible for the concepts in the development of 
the automated test tool GUIdancer. Achim holds a Master in Computer Science 
and has worked with the University of Braunschweig and Digital Equipment as 
a technical consultant. </p>
		
	]]> </bio>

	<affiliation> <![CDATA[ <p>
		
Since 1987, BREDEX GmbH has been providing high quality information technology
services in the areas of consultancy, analysis and design, software development and
training. Based in Braunschweig, the company has a history of long term customer
satisfaction and a focus on forward thinking, developing individual solutions that bring
future standards to current project needs. BREDEX sells GUIdancer, which is a powerful
and cost effective automatic test tool for Java and HTML applications. </p>
	
	]]>
	</affiliation>

</boardmember>