<boardmember id="pearce" type="addin">

	<name> Shawn Pearce </name>

	<title> Software Engineer </title>

	<image>pearce.jpg  </image>

	<email> sop@google.com </email>

	<eclipse_affiliation> <![CDATA[
		Solutions Provider
	]]> </eclipse_affiliation>

	<vision>  <![CDATA[

<p>Entering 2010 the Eclipse Foundation is facing many challenges.
</p>

<p>The number of projects that desire to join a release train
has been increasing every year, placing more work on the IP team
during each release cycle.  The development process needs to evolve
and become more streamlined, so that more projects can join the
foundation, follow its development model, and still release as
part of the release train.  Wayne Beaton has already proposed some
changes, and as a board member I will support these efforts, and
continue to encourage further process improvements.</p>

<p>The foundation is dealing with increasingly difficult revenue
issues.  As a trade association dependent upon membership dues,
the foundation relies upon its membership to pay all of its
operating costs.  But, as membership fluctuates due to external
market conditions, the foundation finds itself struggling to
meet member requests.  Going forward the board needs to help the
foundation identify ways to diversify revenue, and make membership
a more valuable investment for all of the member companies.</p>

<p>New contributors are the life-blood of any open source project,
but are often road-blocked gaining commit access to repositories.
Modern distributed systems often alleviate this by permitting change
recording at outside locations until IP agreements can be finished
and access granted.  As the Eclipse Foundation and its members
are very careful with their IP review processes, the foundation
needs to encourage use of tools that make it easier for newcomers
to enter the ecosystem and meet the requirements, without losing
effort, history, or becoming frustrated and leaving.  Moving the
foundation's repositories from CVS/SVN to Git is a huge leap forward,
and something I will continue to support while on the board.</p>

	]]> </vision>

	<bio> <![CDATA[

<p>At Google, Shawn is committed to fostering the growth of the open
source ecosystem by supporting existing programs such as Google
Summer of Code, and the development of new communities, like the
Android Open Source Project.  Prior to joining Google, Shawn lead
a development team at Bank of America building domain-specific
plugins for the Eclipse platform.</p>

<p>Outside of work, Shawn is an active contributor in the Git
community, pushing the limits of distributed development tools.</p>

	]]> </bio>

	<affiliation> <![CDATA[
		Google
	]]>
	</affiliation>

</boardmember>